thieme.com 2018-08-31

# privacy-policy-statement-Thieme-Publishers-New-York-EN

The protection of personal data and subsequently of your privacy is of utmost importance to the Thieme Group. That is why we would like to inform you how we use and protect your data. For the Thieme Group, it goes without saying that all relevant legal provisions will be adhered to in order to guarantee the highest possible level of protection for your privacy. Please read the following information carefully.

**Name and contact data of the persons responsible for data processing and in-house data protection officer**

This data privacy statement is valid for data processing by

Thieme Medical Publishers, Inc.  
333 Seventh Avenue, 18th Floor  
New York, NY 10001  
USA  
Phone +1 212 760 0888   
email:customerservice@thieme.com 

The Thieme Medical Publishers Inc. is controller according to Article 4 No. 7 GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation).

Representative in the European Union with regard to data processing is: 

Georg Thieme Verlag KG  
Rüdigerstraße 14, 70469 Stuttgart  
Germany  
tel: +49 (0)711 - 8931-0  
fax: +49 (0)711 - 8931-298  
email: [kundenservice@thieme.de](mailto:kundenservice@thieme.de)

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our data privacy statement or any other concerns regarding data processing, you can contact the above mentioned address or

**Collection, processing and use of personal data and subsequent processing method**

a) Visiting our website

When you access our website, the browser used on your device will automatically send information to our website server. This information will be saved temporarily in a so-called log file. The following information will be recorded, without you needing to take any further action, and will be saved until automatic deletion:

  * IP address of the computer accessing the data
  * Date and time of access
  * Name and URL of the data accessed
  * Website used for access (referrer URL)
  * Browser used and, if necessary, the operating system of your computer as well as the name of your access provider

The aforementioned data will be processed by us for the following purposes:

  * Guaranteeing a smooth connection establishment and a comfortable use of our website,
  * Evaluation of system security and stability as well as
  * for further administrative purposes.

The legal basis for data processiong is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest is a consequence of the above mentioned purposes. Data will not be used to draw conclusions about your identity.

b) Newsletter

If you have explicity given consent to the use of your email according to Article 6(1)(a) GDPR, we will use it to provide you with our regular newsletters for the area of interests selected by you. In order to receive the newsletter, it is sufficient to provide us with an email address. The provision of further personal data is optional. We will use them to personalize the newsletters.

You can always unsubscribe by using the link listed at the end of every newsletter. No additional costs will occur other than those, according to the standard rates, for the transfer of your cancellation message. You will then no longer receive the canceled newsletters. _The lawfulness of the already carried out communication is not affected by the cancellation.  _

At the above mentioned email address, you can also have your data corrected or deleted.

c) Use of our contact form

We offer you the possibility of contacting us via the forms provided on our website, e.g. if you are an author. For this, the entry of a valid email address is necessary so that we can identify the source of this query and reply accordingly. The addition of further information is optional.

Data processing for the purpose of contacting us is in compliance with Article 6(1)(a) GDPR on the basis of your optional given consent.

Personal data collected by us for the use of the contact form will be deleted after our completion of your inquiry.

d) Ordering goods, online services or other services

The online shop integrated into our website offers you the possibility of ordering goods, online services and other services. Within the ordering process, personal data will be collected by us, especially your name, address and bank data depending on the payment method selected. We will use the data submitted by you to fulfill and process your order, for granting access to online services or for the realization of any other services. When you place an order in our webshop, you will receive a confirmation of the receipt of your order including the contractual wording and your order details via email (acknowledgement of your order). You can save this in your account, it will also be saved by us. Due to security reasons, you will not be able to access your order details via internet, i.e. the webshop, after your order has been shipped. Furthermore, we will use your data to inform you via newsletter, if applicable, about our other products and services that could be of interest to you (see also the “Newsletter” paragraph). You can unsubscribe any time by using the link listed at the end of every newsletter. Additional costs will not occur other than those, according to the standard rates, for the transfer of your cancellation message. You will then no longer receive the canceled newsletters. _The lawfulness of the already carried out communication is not affected by the cancellation.  _

e) Use of our electronic offers

During the use of our electronic offers, e.g. Examen Online, CNE or CME, we will collect personal data, in particular your name, email address and postal address, information about your studies or your professional position. Depending on the offer, your usage will be analyzed so that you can check and, if neccessary, document your learning success.

f) Manuscript submission

For the publication process of scientific articles and contributions in our professional journals and other media, we offer you web-based software support for submitting, checking and processing. In this context, we will collect personal data from you as author, reviewer, editor or as other party involved in the publication process, in particular your name, your address, your email address, your professional position as well as information on potential conflicts of interest in connection with the publications. These data will be used by us for the handling of the publication process and will be usually published together with the article or contribution. With that, besides the editors of the respective publication medium, European and non-European reviewers and other persons or service providers involved in the process will obtain access to the data in the framework of potential peer review or copy editing of your article or contribution.

We cooperate with different service providers, e.g.

  1. ScholarOne und Publons   
Clarivate Analytics US LLC   
1500 Spring Garden   
Philadelphia, PA 19130   
USA   
<http://scholarone.com/products/manuscript/>  
<https://clarivate.com/wp-content/uploads/pdf/privacy-statement-en.pdf>  
_  
_
  2. Manuscript Manager   
Akron ApS   
Gammeltoftsgade 12B, kld.   
1353 Copenhagen   
DENMARK   
  3. Editorial Manager  
Aries Systems Corporation   
50 High Street, Suite 21   
North Andover, MA 01845   
USA   
<https://www.ariessys.com/about/privacy-policy/>
  4. Filestage   
Filestage GmbH  
Heidehofstr. 9   
70184 Stuttgart   
GERMANY   
<https://filestage.io/data-privacy>

Your personal data as well as data of your article or contribution will be transferred to a server of the service provider, stored and processed there. If this occurs within the EU (ScholarOne, Editorial Manager, Manuscript Manager), the service providers have been either certified under the Privacy Shield agreement or have been bound contractually by us in a similar way and thus guarantee that European data privacy law will be adhered to.

Data processing in the framework of the publication process will take place according to Article 6(1)(b) GDPR.

#### Social Networks

Online presence in social media

We entertain online presence within social networks and platforms to communicate with our active customers, prospects and users and to inform them about our services. When you access the respective networks and platforms, the terms of service and data processing of the respective providers apply.

  1. XING (XING SE): <https://www.xing.com/privacy>
  2. LinkedIn (LinkedIn Ireland U.C.): <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>
  3. Youtube (Google LLC): <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de>
  4. Facebook (Facebook Ireland Ltd.): <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>
  5. Twitter (Twitter International Company): <https://twitter.com/de/privacy>
  6. Instagram (Instagram LLC) <https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388>

We process your data if you communicate with us within the social networks and platforms, e.g. create contributions within our online presence or send us messages.

**Use of AddThis Plugins (e.g. “Share“ button)**

In parts, **so-called** s **ocial plugins (“plugins“) of the AddThis bookmarking service** are used on our websites based on Article 6(1)(f) GDPR, which is operated by AddThis LLC, Inc. 8000 Westpark Drive, Suite 625, McLean, VA 2210, USA (“AddThis“). The plugins are usually marked with an AddThis logo, e.g. in the shape of a white plus sign on orange background. An overview of the AddThis plugins and their looks can be found here: <https://www.addthis.com/get/sharing> When you open one of our websites that contains such a plugin, you browser will automatically establish a direct connection to the AddThis servers. The contents of the plugin will be directly sent to your browser by AddThis and integrated into the site. Through this integration, AddThis will receive the information that your browser has called the respective page on our website and will save a cookie on your device to identify your browser. This information (including your IP address) will be directly sent from your browser to an AddThis server in the U.S. and saved there. AddThis will use the data to create anonymized user profiles which will serve as the basis for personalized and interest-focused marketing for visitors of websites with AddThis plugins.

Please read the AddThis data privacy statement <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy> to learn more about the extent and purposes of data collection, processing and usage by AddThis. If you want to object to data collection by AddThis going forward, you can set a so-called opt out cookie which can be downloaded with the following link: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out> You can also completely block the loading of the AddThis Plugins by using add-ons for your browser, e.g. with the “NoScript“ (<http://noscript.net/>) script blocker.

**Use of Google Analytics**

Based on our legitimate interest in analyzing, optimizing and in the commercial operation of our online business according to Article 6(1)(f) GDPR, we are using Google Analytics, a web analytics service by Google LLC (“Google“). Google is using cookies. The information, created by cookies, about the use of our online offers by our users are normally sent to a Google server in the U.S. and saved there. Google has been certified under the Privacy Shield Frameworks and thus guarantees to adhere to the European data privacy laws ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)). Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our online offers, to compile reports about the activities within our online offers and to provide further services to us that are connected with the use of our online offers and internet usage. For this, pseudonymous user profiles of the users can be created from the processed data. We only use Google Analytics with activated IP anonymization. This means that the users‘ IP addresses will be shortened by Google in the European Union member states or in other countries that are members of the “Agreement creating the European Economic Area (EEA Agreement)”. In exceptional cases only, the full IP address will be sent to a server in the U.S. and shortened there. The IP addresses transmitted by the user’s browser will not be merged with other Google data. Users can prevent the storage of the cookies through a respective setting in their browser software. In addition, users can block the collection and processing of those data by Google which were created by the cookie and which refer to the use of our online offers by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>. Further information on data usage by Google, potential settings and options how to object can be found on the Google websites: <https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/partners> (“How Google uses information from sites or apps that use our services“), <http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads> (“Data usage for advertising“), <http://www.google.de/settings/ads> (“Manage information Google is using to display ads for you“).

You can prevent the registration by Google Analytics if you click on the link below. An opt out cookie will be set that prevents the future collection of your data when you visit this website:

Disable Google Analytics

Further information on terms of service and data privacy can be found at <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html> or at <https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/>. We would like to point out that Google Analytics was enhanced with the “anonymizeIp“ code on this website in order to guarantee the anonymized collection of IP addresses (so-called IP masking).

**Use of Webtrends**

Some of our websites are using Webtrends Analytics, a web analytics service of the Webtrends Inc., 555 SW Oak Street, Suite 300, Portland Oregon 97206, USA ("Webtrends") as an alternative to Google Analytics. Webtrends is using so-called "cookies", text files which are saved on your computer and which make it possible to analyze the use of the website by you. The information about your usage of this website generated by the cookie is normally transferred to a Webtrends server in the U.S. and saved there. Through the server-side IP anonymization on this website, your IP address is shortened by Webtrends (“IP masking“) and not stored in full. On behalf of the operator of this website, Webtrends will continue to use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to create reports about the activities on the website and to render services to the website operator which are connected to website and internet usage. You can block the storage of cookies by a respective setting in your browser software. However, we would like to point out that, in this case, you will not be able to use all functionalities of this website.

You can block the collection by Webtrends by clicking on the following link. An opt out cookie will be set that will block the future collection of your data: <https://ondemand.webtrends.com/support/optout.asp?action=out>[ ](https://ondemand.webtrends.com/support/optout.asp?action=out)

Further information on terms of service and data privacy can be found at <https://www.webtrends.com/terms-policies/privacy-statement/>.

**Use of Mouseflow**

Some of our websites use Mouseflow, a web analysis tool of the Mouseflow ApS, Flaesketorvet 68, 1711 Copenhagen, Denmark, to register randomly selected visits (only with anonymized IP address). This will create a protocol of mouse movements, mouse clicks and keyboard interaction with the intention to describe random individual visits of this website as so-called session replays as well as evaluate them as so-called heat maps and to derive potential improvements for this website from this. Data registered by Mouseflow are not personal and will not be forwarded to third parties. Storage and processing of the collected data is taking place within the EU. If you do not wish any data collection by Mouseflow, you can withdraw from it on all websites using Mouseflow, by clicking the following link: [https://mouseflow.de/opt-out/](https://mandrillapp.com/track/click/12718607/mouseflow.de?p=eyJzIjoiZGhhRFQxZUtGZV9uUzRHakkwdjRROHk4SDZJIiwidiI6MSwicCI6IntcInVcIjoxMjcxODYwNyxcInZcIjoxLFwidXJsXCI6XCJodHRwczpcXFwvXFxcL21vdXNlZmxvdy5kZVxcXC9vcHQtb3V0XFxcL1wiLFwiaWRcIjpcIjQ1NGNlODFkYmUyMzQ5MTNiZGM2ZjMwMDMyZDgxOWQ4XCIsXCJ1cmxfaWRzXCI6W1wiNTEzNmIwNDFiM2EzN2MxY2U5NzQ3ZmI0MjdlODJmYjU0ZWFiMGRhOVwiXX0ifQ).

**Adition**

We are using the adserver technology Adition by ADITION technologies AG, Oststraße 55, 40211 Düsseldorf, Germany. Adition uses cookies to control and optimize the display of ads in the context of remarketing. Adition does not store any personal data such as name, email addresses or other personal information by setting cookies. All information is anonymized and contains technical information such as display frequency and display date of ads, the browser used or the installed operating system. Data by Adition will only be transmitted to and processed on servers located in the European Union. Data transfer to third parties will only take place due to legal regulations or in the context of order data processing. Further information on the data privacy guidelines by ADITION can be found at [www.adition.com/kontakt/datenschutz/.](http://www.adition.com/kontakt/datenschutz/) The collection of anonymized data will be stopped when you click on the following link: [www.adition.com/kontakt/datenschutz/?optout=trueAdTraxx](http://www.adition.com/kontakt/datenschutz/?optout=trueAdTraxx) _._

**Use of VG Wort measuring methods**

Some of our websites use VG Wort „Skalierbare Zentrale Messverfahren“ (SZM) by INFOnline GmbH (INFOnline GmbH, Brühler Str. 9, D-53119 Bonn, Germany.) for the determination of statistical values regarding the copy probability of texts. Anonymous measurements are made for this. The access count measurements alternatively use a session cookie or a signature which is created from automatically transmitted information of your browser to recognize computer systems. IP addresses will only be processed in anonymized form. The procedure was developed taking into account data privacy regulations. The only goal of the procedure is to determine the copy probability of individual texts. Individual users will not be identified at any given time. Their identity will always be protected. They will not receive any ads via the system. Many of our sites are using JavaScript requests which are used to send access data to Verwertungsgesellschaft Wort (VG Wort). This makes it possible that our authors participate in the payouts by VG Wort which secure the legal pay for the use of copyrighted material according to (53) UrhG. User usage and metadata will be processed for this, and IP addresses will be shortened while the measurement processes are pseudonymous in this. The shortened IP addresses will be stored for a maximum of 60 days. Usage data in connection with a pseudonymous identifier will be stored for a maximum of six months. In addition to that, users are provided with an opt out to withdraw from data collection for the above mentioned purposes: <https://optout.ioam.de/>. Further information can be found in the INFOnline data privacy statement <https://www.infonline.de/datenschutz/benutzer/>.

**Integration of the Trusted Shops trust badge**

In order to display our Trusted Shops seal of approval and the Trusted Shops products for customers after having placed an order, the Trusted Shops trust badge has been embedded on this website. This serves to preserve our legitimate interests, prevalent in the framework of consideration of interests, in optimal marketing of our offers according to Article 6(1)(f) GDPR. The trust badge and all services marketed with it are a product of the Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15C, 50823 Köln, Germany. When you call up the trust badge, the web server will automatically store a so-called server log file which contains e.g. your IP address, date and time of the call up, data volume sent, and the provider requesting the data (access data) and which documents the call. These access data will not be evaluated and will be overwritten seven days after your website visit at the latest. Further personal data will only be sent to Trusted Shops if you have agreed to it, decided for the Trusted Shop products after having placed your order or have already registered to use them. In this case, the contractual agreement between you and Trusted Shops applies.

**Forwarding personal data, Credit check**

We only forward your personal data to third parties,

if

  * you have explicitly agreed according to Article 6(1)(a) GDPR,
  * forwarding is required to assert, exert or defend legal claims according to Article 6(1)( f) GDPR and there is no reason to believe that you have some mainly protective interest in not having your data forwarded,
  * forwarding is legally required according to Article 6(1)(c) GDPR, and
  * it is legal and required for the processing of the contractual relationship with you according to Article 6(1)(b) GDPR, e.g. your data will be forwarded to the shipping company selected for the actual delivery. To process your payments, we forward your payment data to the bank responsible for processing the payment. If we deliver up front, we will carry out a credit check at SCHUFA Holding AG, Kormoranweg 5, 65201 Wiesbaden, Germany, to protect our legitimate interests, if necessary. Your protective interests will be considered according to legal provisions. Your data will not be forwarded to other third parties.

**Use of cookies**

Various websites are using cookies. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your device. They will not create any damage and do not contain any of your personal data. The information stored in cookies makes it possible for us to identify your device during your next visit. This is conducive to usability and will make the use of our website easier for you. Data processed by cookies are required for the above mentioned purposes to protect our and third parties’ legitimate interests according to Article 6(1)(f) GDPR. You can set up your browser so that you will be informed about the setting of cookies, and decide on a case by case basis if you want to accept them or block them in general. If you deactivate cookies in general, you might not be able to use all functionalities of our website.

You can deactivate individual cookies of our following collaboration partners:

Doubleclick: <https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?hl=de>

M.P Newmedia: <https://www.mp-newmedia.com/opt-out>

Facebook remarketing <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_=_>

**Your rights as the person affected by data processing**

You have the right

  * according to Article 15 GDPR to request full disclosure regarding your personal data processed by us. In particular, you can request full disclosure regarding purposes of processing, category of personal data, categories of recipients who received or will receive your data, planned storage time, existence of a right to correct, delete, limit processing or withdrawal, the existence of a right to appeal, origin of your data if they were not collected by us, and regarding the existence of an automated decision process including profiling and meaningful information regarding their details, if necessary;
  * according to Article 16 GDPR to request the immediate correction of incorrect data or completion of your personal data stored with us;
  * according to Article 17 GDPR to request the deletion of your personal data stored with us if data processing is not required to exert the right of freedom of expression and information, to fulfill a legal obligation, to protect public interest or to assert, exert and defend legal claims;
  * according to Article 18 GDPR to request limited processing of your personal data if the correctness of the data is being disputed by you, data processing is illegal, but you deny the deletion of the data, and if we do not need the data anymore, but require them for asserting, exerting and defending legal interests or if you filed an objection against data processing according to Article 21 GDPR;
  * according to Article 20 GDPR to receive your personal data you provided us with in a structured, well-established and machine-readable format or to request the transmission to another responsible person;
  * according to Article 7(3) GDPR withdraw your already given consent towards us at any time. As a consequence, we are not allowed to continue data processing based on that consent in future and
  * according to Article 77 GDPR file a complaint with a supervisory authority. Normally you can contact the supervisory authority of your place of residence, of your workplace or of our publishing house headquarters.

**Right of withdrawal**

Provided that your personal data are processed based on legitimate interest according to Article 6(1)(f) GDPR, you have the right of withdrawal against the processing of your personal data according to Article 21, in case there are reasons which result from your particular situation or if the withdrawal concerns direct marketing. In the latter case you have the general right of withdrawal which is accepted by us without the statement of a particular reason.

Should you exercise your right of withdrawal, it is sufficient that you send an email to

**Data security**

During your visit to our website, we use the SSL procedure (Secure Socket Layer) in connection with the highest respective level of encryption supported by your browser. Normally this will be 256 Bit encryption. If your browser does not support 256 Bit encryption, we will use the 128 Bit v3 technology. Whether an individual page of our website is transmitted in encrypted fashion, you will recognize by the display of the key or lock icon in the status bar of your browser.

We furthermore utilize suitable technical and organizational security measures to protect your data against manipulation, partial or complete loss, destruction or the unauthorized access by third parties. Our security measures will be constantly improved following the most recent technological developments.

**Timeliness and modification of this data privacy statement**

This data privacy statement is currently valid as of May 2018.

The development of our website or our offers, or new legal or official guidelines can make it necessary to modify this data privacy statement. The most current data privacy statement can always via accessed and printed by you on our website at https://www.thieme.de/de/thieme-gruppe/Datenschutzerklaerungen-alle-DE.htm
